Grace Lee

UX DESIGNER | EDUCATOR | INSTRUCTIONAL DESIGNER

graceavocado.com
gracelee.ux@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am an Instructional Designer with a background in UX Design and Education, interested in the intersection of learning and technology. I have experience working in private schools, colleges, tutoring centers, outreach programs, museums, and EdTech startups.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2019

Chef Koochooloo - UI/UX, Instructional Design | Mountain View, CA

- $\bullet\,$ Product manager leading a team of UX designers and illustrators for the app
- Created low and mid fidelity wireframes for the fourth grade curriculum
- Designed curriculum and user tested them by going to schools and teaching them to children, and observing how they react to the framework of this program

2019-Present

Dunamis Harvest GM - Website Designer | Remote

• Designed websites and logos for the organization using CSS, HTML, JavaScript

2017-Present

Gallagher Learning Center - Educator | Saratoga, CA

- Created curriculum for online courses and in person tutoring, preparing students for the SATs, ACTs, ISEE, and HSPT exams
- Evaluated students' capacity and structured classes according to their needs

2016-2017

Mural Arts Program - Graduate Assistant | Philadelphia, PA

- Designed information brochures and educational art posters using Photoshop and InDesign
- Organized data gathered from Program participants collected from surveys

2014-2016

Lydian Academy - Teacher | Menlo Park, CA

- Designed course curriculum for English and Social Studies classes in the middle school and high school level, and taught AP Language & Composition and AP English Literature
- Taught Math classes from Algebra I to Precalculus

2014

LA Museum of the Holocaust - Getty Multicultural Education

Intern | Los Angeles, CA

- Created an interactive audio tour by conducting interviews of Holocaust survivors and aligning their story with the museum layout
- Researched and created a tour about the Shanghai Ghettos

2011-2012

UCLA Office of Residential Life - Student Leader | Los Angeles, CA

- Planned educational and recreational programs with Residential Assistants
- Managed the year's budget for Hitch Suites Residential Area, and brought the budget out of deficit spending
- Discussed and approved of funding for school programs throughout the UCLA campus

EDUCATION

2019

Bloc

UX Design Program

2017

University of Pennsylvania

Learning Science Technology, M.S.Ed

2014

UCLA

Linguistics & Asian Languages and Cultures, B.S. Comparative Literature, B.A. Computer Science, Minor

Tools & SKILLS

Curriculum Design
Teaching/Tutoring
Adult Learning Theory
Project Management
Visual Design
UX/UI Design
User Research & Testing
Personas & User Stories
Wireframing & Prototyping
Adobe Creative Suite
Sketch | Figma | Adobe XD
HTML | CSS | Javascript

LANGUAGES

English • Advanced Korean • Intermediate Japanese • Basic